[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我答应过你一些好的部分。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I promised you some good parts.
我们终于找到了一个好的部分
We're finally getting to a good part and
这可能是你没有经验的事情。
this is something that you probably don't have experience with.
这就是所谓的结束。
It's something called closure.
它也称为词法作用域或静态作用域。
It's also called Lexical Scoping or Static Scoping.
这是函数的结果，这些函数可以嵌套和
It's a consequence of functions that can nest and
函数是第一类值，JavaScript有它，
functions that are first class values, and JavaScript has it,
并且在实现它们的方式上几乎完全正确，并且
and is almost completely right in the way it implements them, and
这可能是编程语言中最好的特性。
it's maybe the best feature ever put into a programming language.
内部函数的上下文包括外部函数的范围和
The context of an inner function includes the scope of the outer function and
内部函数即使在外部函数具有
the inner function enjoys that context even after the outer function has
回来了。
returned.
我认为这句话对你毫无意义，我理解这一点。
I expect that statement made no sense to you at all and I understand that.
所以，我将不得不分步骤地解释这一点。
So, I'm gonna have to explain this in steps.
因此，我们将从观察到函数作用域类似于块作用域开始。
So, we'll start with the observation that functions scope works like block scope.
因此，您熟悉块作用域的概念。
So, you're familiar with the idea of block scope.
因此，明年，我们可能会在我们的大多数系统中使用let语句。
So next year, we'll probably have let statements in most of our systems.
在这里，我们有两个街区。
And here, we've got two blocks.
一个在另一个内部，内部块可以看到它的变量，并且
One inside of the other and the inner block can see its variables, and
外部块的变量。
the variables of the outer block.
外部块只能看到自己的变量。
The outer block can only see its own variables.
因此，我假设每个人都对块作用域的想法感到满意。
So, I assume everybody is comfortable with the idea of block scope.
我们从1960年就开始这样做了，这很棒。
We've had that since 1960 and it's great.
所以，我们可以对函数做同样的事情。
So, we can do the same thing with functions.
您可以将函数简单地看作是一个带有一点额外内容的块
You can think of a function as simply being a block with a little bit of extra
附加到它的机制，以便将来可以调用它。
mechanism attached to it, so that you can invoke it in the future.
你不需要马上去做，同样的关系也适用。
That you don't have to do it immediately and the same relationships apply.
所以我们得到了黄色函数，它可以看到AND
So we've got the yellow function, which can see a and
B和只能看到a的绿色函数。
b and the green function that can only see a.
完全相同的关系，我们可以将这种关系表示为集合。
Exactly the same relationship and we can represent this relationship as sets.
所以，这是外部函数可以看到的变量集，
So, this is the set of variables that the outer function can see and
这是内部函数可以看到的变量集。
this is the set of variables that the inner function can see.
这里没有什么令人惊讶的，除了我们可以用这样的方式来描述这种关系
Nothing surprising here, except that we can describe this relationship in that
内部函数的变量集包含外部函数的集和
the set of variables of the inner function encloses the set of the outer function and
这就是为什么我们称之为结束。
that's why we call this closure.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我们称它为闭合有点太糟糕了，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: And it's kinda too bad that we call it closure,
因为大多数人认为结束是另一回事，
cuz most people think of closure as meaning something else,
比如报复或者复仇。
like retribution or vengeance.
已经成为受害者，但我得到了一些了结，感觉会很好。
Have been victimized, but I'm getting me some closure and it's gonna feel good.
但这不是那种结束，但这就是我们所说的。
But it's not that kind of closure, but that's what we're calling it.
所以，我们有点被困在这一点上，这似乎是一个简单的想法。
So, we're kind of stuck with that and it seems like a simple idea.
只需添加嵌套函数，它们应该具有明显的关系，
Just add nested functions, which have what should be an obvious relationship,
因为示波器的工作方式，但是花了很长时间，
because of the way that scope works, but it took a long,
这个想法需要很长时间才能得到发展。
long time for this idea to get developed.
所以，你需要一种有三个条件的语言。
So, you needed a language that had three things.
他需要词汇范围。
He needed lexical scoping.
他需要嵌套函数和函数作为第一类值。
He needed nested functions and functions, as first class values.
在很早的时候，我们有三个函数中的两个，
And pretty early on, we got functions that would have two out of three,
但是我们没有得到一个函数，它包含了所有这三个元素，直到Scheme。
but we didn't get a function that had all three until scheme.
计划是麻省理工学院的一项尝试
Scheme was an experiment at MIT in an attempt
去理解卡尔·休伊特在他们70岁出头时的模特。
to understand Carl Hewitt's after model in their early 70s.
实验失败了，因为他们从来没有听懂卡尔在说什么
The experiment failed in that they never did understand what Carl was talking
但是他们确实发现了这种新的编程方式，
about, but they did discover this new way of programming,
我认为这是计算机史上最重要的突破。
which I think was the most important breakthrough in the history of computing.
就像所有真正重要的重大突破一样，
And like all of the really important, significant breakthroughs,
世界根本没有注意到这一点。
the world took no notice of it whatsoever.
事实上，我们花了两代人才最终弄明白
And in fact, it took two generations before we finally figured out
这是一个好主意，并把它带到了主流，但它总是
that this was a good idea and brought it to the mainstream, but it was always
一个好主意和花了这么长时间的原因就是这个问题。
a good idea and the reason it took so long was because of this problem.
所以，我们得到了和以前一样的东西，我们得到了一个内部函数，
So, we've got the same thing we had before where we got an inner function and
外部函数。
an outer function.
但这一次，内部函数在外部函数的执行中幸存下来，
But this time, the inner function survives the execution of the outer function,
因为外部函数返回内部函数。
because the outer function is returning the inner function.
所以我们将调用green函数，它将在堆栈上分配一个。
So we will call the green function, it'll allocate a on the stack.
它将返回一个新函数并退出。
It will return a new function and exit.
现在我们想调用它返回的黄色函数，但是
Now we want to call the yellow function that it returned, but
黄色函数希望访问，但堆栈上不再有。
yellow function wants access to a, but a is no longer on the stack.
砰。
Boom.
我们花了20年，40年的时间才找到解决这个问题的办法。
It took us 20 years, 40 years to figure out what to do about this.
原来解决方案是微不足道的。
Turns out the solution is trivial.
不要使用库存，分配堆上的所有激活记录。
Don't use a stock, allocate all of the activation records on the heap.
找一个好的垃圾收集器，完成。
Get a good garbage collector, done.
真的，真的很容易，但花了很长时间才弄明白。
Really, really easy, but it took a long time to figure this out.
&gt；&gt；演讲者2：你能重复这个解决方案吗？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Can you repeat that solution?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，不要在堆栈上分配激活记录。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, don't allocate the activation records on the stack.
在堆上分配它们。
Allocate them on the heap.
找一个好的垃圾收集器，完成。
Get a good garbage collector, done.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：就是这样。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: That's it.
这就是整件事。
That is the whole whole thing.
无论如何，这个想法是在方案中发现的。
So anyway, this idea is discovered in scheme.
需要很长时间才能最终成为主流。
Takes a long time for to finally get to the mainstream.
有没有人碰巧知道把这个想法带到这个想法的第一个语言是什么？
Anybody happen to know what was the first language to bring this idea to
主流是什么？
the mainstream was?
有人吗？
Anybody?
这个JavaScript
This JavaScript.
JavaScript是第一种这样做的语言，紧随其后的是Python和
Javascript was the first language to do this followed quickly by Python and
Ruby，C#明白了
Ruby, C# got it.
最终，C+得到了它。
Eventually, C++ got it.
PHP用一种真正的半途而废的方式做到了这一点，但他们去年才得到它。
PHP does it in a really half-assed way, but they got it just last year.
Java终于得到了它。
Java finally got it.
Java很难跟上他愚蠢的弟弟，但是
Java was having a tough time keeping up with his stupid little brother, but
它终于得到了这个。
it finally got this.
这个想法花了很长时间才成为主流，以至于有一种观点认为，
This idea took so long to get to the mainstream that there was an opinion that,
嗯，它没有进入主流，因为这不是一个好主意。
well, it's not getting to the mainstream, cuz it's not a good idea.
这不是一个好主意的证据是它还没有被采纳，但是
The proof that it's not a good idea is that it hasn't been adopted, but
我们现在正在采用它，我们正在采用它，因为事实证明它是
we're now adopting it and we're adopting it, because it turns out it's
我们现在遇到的很多问题的解决方案。
the solution to a lot of the problems that we're having now.
处理分布式系统和异步性，以及
Dealing with distributed systems and asynchronicity, and
如果您有为您工作的函数，那么我们现在做的事情要容易得多。
the things that we do now much easier if you've got functions working for you.
在这个特定的模式中，我们有一个函数比另一个函数存活，
And this particular pattern where we have a function that survives another function,
返回函数的函数是一个非常强大的重要函数
a function that returns a function is an incredibly powerful important
建筑。
construction.
它非常有用。
It's amazingly useful.
令人惊讶的强大，我们首先用JavaScript获得了它，
Amazingly powerful and we got it and we got it first with JavaScript,
这真是太棒了。
which is amazing.